Finding Aid for the Farington Family Correspondence LSC.0668
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Folio 8
  - Personal Notes and Correspondence, 1734 May 18 - June 25 1767 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Fourth item is an oblong sheet of paper pasted on top of another sheet, also with writing on it and barely visible through upper layer; the top sheet of paper has heading, "A Paraphrase on Charity the 13th Ch.1 Ep. To the Corinthians".
    Fifth item contains religious verses,
    sixth item is an undated latter from Edward Brailsford to Mrs. Allen at Cookham.
    Seventh item is a remedy/treatment protocol for a medical ailment dated May 26, 1740.
    Eighth item is an undated bifolium-size sheet of paper folded in half to make 4 pages, with writing in Latin.
    Ninth item is a bifolium-size sheet of paper folded in half to make 4 pages, the first two of which are written on; it is undated, has heading "Government of the Thoughts Archbishop of York" and contains writing of a religious nature.
    Tenth item is a folium- sized sheet of paper containing verses which begin with "Conduct the steps of my unguarded youth..."
    Eleventh item is a single sheet of paper with writing on both sides; first side begins, "Sacred to the Remains of Lady Herietta Beard, Only Daughter of [the?] late Earl of Waldegrave in the Year 1734" and date 31 May 1753 at bottom of page. On opposite page is written another eulogy, this one for Mary Basnett, "Daughter of Thomas & Ann Basnett of this Parish died the 10th of Feb. 1756 aged 23."
- Folio 9
  - Correspondence to George Farington, 1775 March 29 - 1779 March 30 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    These papers were not contained in a binder as are most of the other items in this collection.
    On final page, the address "Mr. Geo Farington [?] at Mr. Boydell's Cheapside London".
    The items are partially bound together and consist of letters dated 1775, 1776, and 1779.
    The salutations are simply "Sir" and the letters are signed [Oxford?].
- Folio 10
  - Poster used as binder, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence from Joseph Farington to his relative William Farington and his father Rev. William Farington, 1767 May - 1821 September 3 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    First item is a label-sized slip of paper on which is written "Joseph Farington R.A. / Letter to, and from." All other items are letters of correspondence.
    The second item is a letter on a single sheet of paper dated September 3, 1821 from Joseph Farington to William Farington regarding travel plans.
    The third item is a letter on a single page dated Sept. 20, 1815 from Joseph Farington to "Mrs. Farington", presumably William's wife, informing her of her husband's promotion to the rank of Port Captain.
    The fourth through eighteenth items are all letters from Joseph Farington to William Farington with the following dates:
    August 2, 1815
    June 28 1820 (attached to this letter with a black seal is an invitation dated March 27, 1820)
    March 30, 1815
    March 10, 1815
    January 28, 1815
    March 24, 1808
    February 20, 1808
    January 11, 1808
    July 2, 1807
    July 22, 1807
    October 6, 1806
    June 9, 1806
    December 1805
    September 1799 (a different page of the same letter is a "Copy of a letter from Sir Alan Gardiner" dated September 26, 1799).
    Also included are a letter dated may 1767 from Joseph Farington to his father Rev. William Farington and a letter from Joseph Farington to Lieutenant William Farington dated May 3, 1808.
  - Bookseller's note, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
    "Myer's & Co. (BOOKSELLERS) LTD. / 80, New Bond Street, London, W.1, England." In pen: "In this folder...3 letters from Lord Oxford (Walpole) 1775-79, Letters from Shaw Hall re house parties, references to Lady Derby, [Coka?], Jerningham, etc."
- Folio 11
  - Leather and cardboard binder with string and, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Labeled: "William Farington 8 folders / Early juvenile letters circa 1783 / Very large lettering / Nautical Travels 1783 as far apart as Madras and Brazil".
  - Farington Family Correspondence, 1832 March 19 - 1855 April 18 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Most of the correspondence is addressed to Mrs. Fanny Farington, wife of Captain William Farington.
    The first item is a letter from William Farington to Fanny dated April 27, [?]
    the second item is a letter to Captain Farington from "Syd: S[?]ke"
    the third item is an undated letter from William Farington to his wife Fanny in which he discusses the loss of a ship that makes "Father a ruined man"
    the fourth item is a letter of consolation to Captain Farington from a friend dated March 19, 1832
    the fifth item is a letter to Mrs. Farington from P. Watson dated February 24, 1832
    the sixth letter is undated and addressed to Mrs. Farington
    the seventh letter is dated December 12, 1832 and is from Capt. Farington to his wife
    the eighth letter is dated September 3, 1833 and is addressed to Mrs. Farington
    the ninth letter is dated July 1834 and is addressed to Mrs. Farington from G. Dickenson
    the tenth letter is dated April 18, 1855 and is addressed to Mrs. Farington from Maria Love Robertson
    the eleventh letter is addressed to Mrs. Farington and dated September 25, 1835
    the twelfth letter is dated May 11, 1836 and is from Capt. Farington to his wife
    the thirteenth letter is dated November 8, 1837 and is addressed to William Farington, "To my dear Godson"
    the fourteenth letter is dated November 4, 1839 and is addressed to Mrs. Farington from "A.M. S[?]th"
    the fifteenth letter is dated november 1839 and is addressed to Mrs. Farington from "[?] Gardener"
    the sixteenth letter is dated March 5, 1833 and is from J.A. Farington to E. Farington.
  - Farington Family Correspondence, 1814 June 27 - 1858 February 25 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    All but two of the letters are addressed to William Farington from his father, mother, and sister Frances Ann and other correspondents. These other two are addressed to Edmund Farington). The dates of the letters are: June 27, 1814; August 1, 18[??]; 1838; November 30, 1838; December 20, 1838; April 25, 1838; October 22, 1830; Easter Day, 1839; November 1, 1838; October 26, 1830; 1839; February 25, 1858; September 30, 1838; September 18, 1838; March 18 [????]; October 5, 1838; January 5, 1837; M[?] 29, 1837; October 11, 1838; August 29, 1839; July 25, 1839; December 27, 1839; March 7, 1834; May 13, 1840; March 13, 1840; March 28 [????]; January 13, 1837; March 25, 1840.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1830 May 04 - 1840 May 08 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    These letters are all addressed to William Farington and are mostly from his father, William Farington, mother F.A. Farington, sister Frances Ann and brother Edmund. The dates of the letters are almost all between the years of 1838-1840.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1827 November 08 - 1831 December 15 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    These letters are all addressed to William Farington and are mostly from his father, William Farington, mother Frances A. Farington, brother Richard, brother Edmund, and schoolmate William Macgregor. A letter dated only "July 3" has pencil cartoon sketches of naval figures and a latter dated only "December 9" has Greek writing on it.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1814 February 05 - 1840 May 10 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    These letters are all addressed to William Farington and are mostly from his father, William Farington, mother Frances A. Farington, brother Edmund, sister Frances Ann and brother Joseph Farington.
- Folio 12
  - Binder boards, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1799 November 25 - 1806 January 1806 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    These letters are all addressed to William Farington and are mostly from his father, William Farington, mother Ann Frances Farington, brother George, sister [E.F.], and brother [E.F].
    Often, a single letter will contain correspondence from multiple family members to William Farington.
    All but one of the letters is written between November 25, 1799 and February 27, 1800.
    A letter dated only "February 27" has a note at top: "Copy of a letter from Captn. [Barlow?] to Admiral Kingsmile at Co[?]".
  - Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington, 1800 March 02 - 1808 January 20 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    These letters are addressed to William Farington and George Farington, and some single letters contain correspondence addressed to each.
    The letters are mostly from his father, William Farington, mother Ann Francis Farington and sister [E.F.].
    A letter dated February 6, 1806 has a black wax seal with possible Arabic writing, and a letter dated March 2, 1800 has rough sketches of the Union Jack design.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1803 January 09 - 1804 January 16 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    These letters are all addressed to William Farington from his mother Ann Frances Farington and sister E.F. Farington.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1804 August 08 - 1806 May 18 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    These letters are all addressed to William Farington from his mother Ann Frances Farington and sister E.F. Farington and sister Frances Farington. The letter dated August 26 has a possible Arabic seal in red wax.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1802 January 17 - July 10 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    These letters are all addressed to William Farington from his father, William Farington, mother Anne F. Farington, brother Edmund, and sister E. F. Farington.
    All the letters are bound with string except for a letter dated January 18, 1802 from Edmund Farington which was tucked loose between the first and second bound letters.
    Under the signature of this letter "E. F. Farington" is written in a different hand, "10 years old".
  - Correspondence to William Farington and Henry Farington, 1798 January 11 - 1800 October 14 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    The first letter is addressed to Lieutenant William Farington from E.F. Farington (this part of the letter is written in juvenile script), sister E.F. Farington (mature hand), and mother Ann Farington, and is dated October 14, 1800.
    The second letter is addressed to Henry Farington from his sister E.F. Farington brother George Farington.
    This letter contains the date Jan. 11, 1798, under which is written in a different hand "79 / 19"; in other words, calculating the years between 1798 and 1779.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1802 June 26 - July 14 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    These letters are addressed to William Farington from his father, William Farington, mother Anne F. Farington, sister E. F. Farington, and godson. All the letters are bound with fine string.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1790 August 20 - 1808 January 12 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    These letters are addressed to William Farington from his mother Anne F. Farington, sister E. Frances Farington, sister "Frances Farington", and a friend, Ann [Delamott].
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1807 January 27 - December 11 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    These letters are addressed to William Farington from his mother Anne F. Farington, sister "E.F.L.", brother "E.F.F" and sister "Frances Farington".
    In the letter dated January 27, 1807, in a different hand above a sibling's note is written "Poor Edward, Aged 15".
    The letter with the postal stamp for July 6, 1807 contains the signature "[J?]L."
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1802 November 16 - 1807 September 13 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Both letters are addressed to Lieutenant Farington, RN aboard La Topaze in Jamaica from his sister E.F. Farington.
    The November 16, 1802 letter discusses family matters, including the recent death of their brother George.
    The September 13, 1807 letter discusses personal and family matters as well as literature. In particular, she discusses her enjoyment of Tasso's "Jerusalem Delivered" as well as Cowper and Voltaire. She quotes Voltaire in French in the letter.
  - Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington, 1800 December 1 - 1802 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    These letters are addressed either to William Farington or to George Farington, from their mother Ann Farington, father William Farington, and sister E.F. Farington.
    All but one of the letters is dated between December 1, 1800 and December 16, 1800.
    The letter dated December 11, 1800 contains rough sketches.
  - Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington, 1789 December 14 - 1801 January 07 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    These letters are addressed either to William Farington or to George Farington, from their mother Ann Farington, brother Edmund Farington, sister Frances Farington and sister E.F. Farington.
    The letter dated January 7, 180[1?] is addressed to George Farington aboard the HMS La Topaze, but seems to be addressed to both George and William, who may have both held a commission upon that ship.
    The letter dated 1790 from sister E.F. Farington is written in French in a juvenile hand.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, Jr., 1790 July 01 - 29 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    These letters are all addressed to William Farington, Jr. at Mr. Lane's Academy in Kent. From his mother, Ann Farington. The letter dated July 6, 1790 also contains writing in juvenile hands from two siblings, Henry Farington (7 years old) and sister E.F. Farington (12 years old).
  - Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington, 1801 August 18 - 1809 December 11 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    These letters are addressed either to William Farington or to George Farington, from their mother Ann Farington and/or sister Frances Farington and sister E.F. Farington.
    The letters dated August 18, 1801, August 31, 1801 (there are two), and September 15, 1801 are addressed to George Farington aboard the HMS La Topaze in Jamaica, but contain "William" in the salutation.
    The letter dated August 18, 1801 is headed "August 18, 1800" but has a postal stamp for 1801.
    The letter dated August 16, 1807 has continuous writing for 8 pages (across 2 sheets of paper).
- Folio 13
  - Binder boards, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington, 1801 March 24 - 1805 June 17 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    These letters are addressed either to William Farington or to George Farington, from their mother Ann Farington and/or sister Frances Farington or brother E. Farington.
    Most of the letters are addressed to George Farington aboard the HMS La Topaze in Jamaica, although one occasionally will include a salutation such as "Dear children" from mother Ann Farington, indicating that it is meant for both George and William Farington.
    Many of the letters to George Farington are part of a series of letters written by his sister E.F.F and are numbered in the upper right-hand corner sequentially
    the letter dated March 42, 1801 explains her system of arranging them.
    There is a somewhat later included in this folder that not part of this sequence--it is dated June 17, 1805 and to William Farington aboard the HMS Hibernia from his younger brother E. Farington.
  - Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington, 1800 November 21 - 1802 December 16 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    These letters are addressed either to William Farington or to George Farington, from their father William Farington, mother Ann Farington and/or sister E.F. Farington.
    The letter dated May 5, 1801 is are addressed to George Farington aboard the HMS La Topaze in Jamaica, but contains "William" in the salutation, it also contains "Copies of the letters from Mr. Marsden and Captn. Peddar dated March 180[1?] regarding the HMS La Topaze.
    There are two undated letter fragments from sister E.F. Farington which each contain transcriptions of literary or religious texts, including "A friendly visit to the House of Mourning", Cowper's "Prayer for Patience" and Milton's Lycidas: "So sinks the day-star in the Ocean bed, /And yet anon repairs his drooping head, / And tricks his beams, and with new spangled Ore, / Flames in the forehead of the morning sky." The letter dated December 12, 1802 to William Farington from his father contains an itemized expense list.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1802 December 05 - 12 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    This folder contains three letters and an undated letter fragment to William Farington aboard the Bombay Castle from his mother Ann Farington and sister E.F. Farington.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1801 December 15 - 1802 January 06 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    This folder contains 6 letters, most of which contain correspondence from more than one family member to William Farington aboard the HMS La Topaze in Jamaica.
    The correspondence is from William Farington's father William Farington, mother Ann Farington, sister E.F. Farington, and brother E.F. Farington.
    A letter dated December 15, 1801 from "E.F. Farington" contains the following note: "The fate of my Brother George has afflicted us very much, but it has been a great consolation to us, that you have escaped the horrid fever."
    A letter dated January 5, 1802 contains a transcription of a letter from James Coffin addressed to a "Madam".
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1800 June 17 - 1805 November 16 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    This folder contains 12 letters and letter fragments, most of which contain correspondence from more than one family member to William Farington aboard either the Bombay Castle East Indiamen or the HMS Hibernia (there is also one letter dated October 4, 1802 addressed to William at "Parrs Wood, Didsbury near Manchester").
    The correspondence is from William Farington's father William Farington, mother Ann Farington, sister E.F. Farington, sister Frances Farington, and brother/godson E.F. Farington.
    The letter dated December 28, 1802 contains transcriptions of religious verse.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1803 January 23 -1804 October 26 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    This folder contains 17 letters and letter fragments to William Farington on board the Bombay Castle in China and Bombay from the following members of his family: father William Farington, sister E.F. Farington, sister Frances Farington, and mother Ann Farington.
    The letters dated February 26, 1803; April 3; April 7, 1803 (there are two with this date); April 21, 1803; and April 18, 1803 are bound together with black string.
    The letter dated May 4, 1803 contains, in a different hand, the note: "The last letter from my poor Father / he died on the 30th of July this year 1803 / the date of this is 4 May".
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1802 June 12 - 15 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    The first letter is to William Farington from his mother Ann Farington and is six pages long.
    The second letter is to William Farington aboard HMS La Topaze in Jamaica from his sister E.F. Farington and is 14 pages long.
    This letter includes transcription of letters informing the family of the death abroad of Henry Farington.
  - Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington, 1800 March 09 - 1805 April 05 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    The letters are mostly addressed to William Farington from his mother A. Farington and sister E.F. Farington, except for the letter fragment with the postal stamp May 6, 1801, which is addressed to Mr. George Farington aboard the HMS La Topaze in Jamaica (this letter is paginated at the right upper corner of each page from 5-8) from E.F. Farington.
    Several of the letters are addressed to Lieut. [William] Farington aboard the HMS Plover.
    The letters dated May 19, 1800 and May 21-22, 1800 appear to have been used for scrap paper on which to write drafts of other letters.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1780 May 20 - 1805 June 01 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    The letters in this folder are all to William Farington (most letters are addressed to him aboard either the HMS Plover or HMS Hibernia).
    With the exception of a letter dated May 20, 1780 from his mother Ann, all of the letters are from the years 1800 and 1805.
    The letters are from his father William Farington, mother Ann Farington, sister E.F. Farington, sister Frances, and brother E.F. Farington.
    The letter dated October 14, 1800 is addressed to William aboard the HMS Plover, but this name is crossed out in red ink and replaced with "Resolution".
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1800 June 17 - 1805 March 19 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    The letters are addressed to Lieut. William Farington from his mother A. Farington, sister E.F. Farington, sister Frances Farington and father William Farington.
    The letters all fall into one of two dating periods: from June 17, 1800 to October 3, 1800 (when he was aboard the HMS Plover) or from February 24, 1805 to March 19, 1805 (when he was aboard the HMS Thunderer and the HMS Hibernia).
    The letter dated September 28, 1800 has two pencil sketches of ships on it.
    The letter dated Sept. 2, 1800 contains a transcription of the French "Chanson Clara" by William's sister E.F. Farington.
    The letter dated Sept. 19, 1800 contains writing in both red and brown ink, at top of first page in red ink is written: "Au Lieutenant sans chemise" and a short note in French from his sister E.F.
    The letter dated August 8, 1800, in addition to being crosswritten, contains interlinear writing oriented upside down from the original writing which begins: "My Father tells me, I had better transcribe Hals letter & I think so too, so [once?] more patience brother William / Phoebe at Sea 18 July / My dear father, I am very happy to write to you..."
    The letter fragment dated March 3, 1805 from sister Frances Farington was probably originally part of the same correspondence as the next item, a fragment with the postal stamp March 5, 1805.
  - Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington, 1790 September 03 - 1811 January 07 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    The letters are mostly addressed to William Farington from father William Farington, his mother A. Farington, brother and godson E. Farington, and sister E.F. Farington, except for the letter dated August 3, 1801, which is addressed to Mr. George Farington aboard the HMS La Topaze in Jamaica, but contains correspondence to both George and, presumably, William, since the salutation from their mother is: "My Dear god Children".
    The letter dated January 7, 1811 to Lieut. Farington aboard the HMS Clio is partially torn, but contains a note from [P.?] Hughes in addition to correspondence from William's mother Ann Farington.
    The letters in this folder date to the following years: 1790 (when William Farington was a student at Mr. Lane's Academy), 1800-1801, 1805, 1808-1809, and 1811.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1791 January 28 - 1800 February 02 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    These letters are addressed to William Farington (mostly aboard the HMS Boddam, HMS Plover, or HMS Ruby) from father William Farington, his mother A. Farington, brothers George Farington and Henry Farington, and sister E.F. Farington.
    The letters fall into two groups: those dated from January 28, 1791 to December 5, 1791, and those dated from December 7, 1798 to February 2, 1800.
    The letter dated November 13, 1799 also contains a transcription: "Copy of a letter from Sir Allan Gardner / Royal Sovereign Torbay Nov. 10 " expressing congratulations on William Farrington's promotion to Lieutenant in the Navy.
    The letter dated January 21, 1800 from William's sister E.F. Farington contains a transcription of a French poem "Jeune filles".
  - Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington, 1799 November 08 - 1801 May 31 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    These letters are addressed either to William Farington or to George Farington, from their mother Ann Farington and/or sister Frances Farington.